moderndogmagazine.com 2019-09-05

# Modern Dog Privacy Policy | Modern Dog magazine

Modern Dog Inc. ("Modern Dog") is committed to safeguarding the privacy of all visitors and customers when interacting with any of our communication outlets, such as the website, e-newsletters, digital and print subscriptions, and contests. This privacy policy provides details to you, the user, as to how we collect data and how we use that data to improve your experiences when interacting with us.

By using the Modern Dog website, you agree to the terms of our Privacy Policy and consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information for the purposes set out in this policy. We do reserve the right, without prior notice, to modify our Privacy Policy as business needs require. 

**Collection of Personal Data**  
Modern Dog collects personal data, meaning any information relating to the identity of any individual, when you:  

  * Subscribe to the publications (print and digital);
  * Download and register to read any additional content such as e-books;
  * Subscribe to e-newsletters or participate in any type of online forum;
  * Submit content in any form to be used in our publications, newsletters, on the website, or on Modern Dog’s social media channels
  * Enter any contests, giveaways or promotions
  * Participate in any surveys
  * Contact customer service representatives
  * Apply for a career opportunity

We do require some personal data in order to participate in these above services. If you do not wish to provide such data, you may opt-out at any time; however, you will be limited to what services are available to you. 

Below, you will find comprehensive examples of where and how we collect your personal data. Unless specifically stated otherwise in this Privacy Policy, the data we collect may be used for any purpose set forth in "How We Use the Information We Collect" below.

**_Subscriptions:_**  When you subscribe to Modern Dog, we ask you to provide your name, mailing address, email address, phone number, and credit card or other payment information for the purposes of fulfilling your subscription, sending you invoices, contacting you about the expiry of your subscription, and sending you service messages about your subscription. Once you are subscribed, we may store your subscription information, including its start date, renewal date, pricing, publications, and any customer service contacts you may have with us.

**_Online Registration:_**  You do not have to register to browse some areas of our websites. However, registration may be required to receive online newsletters or to participate in certain website features, such as contests, giveaways, memorials, and community forums. When you register, you will be asked for personal data such as your name, e-mail address, and a user name and password that you select. We collect this information to identify who you are, to provide you with the service or information you requested, and/or to facilitate your participation in a contest, on-line forum or community. We may also use this information for other purposes, such as promotional and marketing purposes, in accordance with this Privacy Policy and not in violation of applicable law.

Please remember that any information you disclose in some of these contests, public forums or community areas becomes public information and is immediately accessible to other users, so it is important for you to carefully consider what, if any, personal data you reveal in these areas. We may use information disclosed by you in this way to promote our products and services in our advertising communications, among other things.

**_Information based on a referral:_**  On our website and through certain promotions, you can submit personal data about other people. For example, if you order a gift subscription and want it sent directly to the recipient, you would be required to submit the recipient's name and address. We do not use the recipient's personal data for any other purpose unless this is consistent with any further dealings which we may have with the recipient directly. 

**_Promotions or Surveys:_**  When you enter a contest or promotion or participate in a survey or poll we may ask you to provide your name, address, phone number, and email address. We use the information we collect on promotion entry forms to administer your participation in the promotions and for other purposes stated on the entry form. Our surveys ask for opinions on various issues and may be sponsored by our advertisers and partners. Information obtained through surveys is aggregated and used internally. We also share survey information with advertisers and marketing partners in an aggregated form that does not personally identify you. In the event personal information is requested as part of a survey, such personal information will only be provided to unaffiliated third parties if you have given consent.

**_Optional Information:_**  Occasionally, we may request demographic information (age or gender) or information about your interests (pets, age, breed) and purchasing preferences. In most instances, you do not have to provide us with this information to receive the publications, product, or service you have requested. When demographic information is required, it will be indicated, such as by an asterisk (*). We use this demographic and preference information to, among other things, tailor or improve our messaging, publications, product and service offerings, including our offerings to you where this is in accordance with this Privacy Policy, as well as for internal marketing research purposes.

**_Customer Service:_  **When you call one of our customer service representatives, or email us with a comment or question, you may be asked for information that identifies you, such as your name, mailing address, account number, postal or zip code, and telephone number, to help us promptly answer your question. We retain this information as necessary to assist you in the future, for instance with any further queries you may have. We also use your feedback, suggestions and comments to monitor and/or improve our messaging, publications, product offerings, and Services, among other things.

**_Website Information:_**  We collect the IP (Internet protocol) addresses of all visitors to our website, as well as clickstream and other related information, such as information about your computer or device, web browser and operating system and their settings, the referring page that linked you to our site, the pages, content or ads you see or click on during your visit and when and for how long you do so, items you download, the next website you visit when you leave our site, and any search terms you have entered on our site. We use this information to monitor and improve our Services, among other things.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**  
**_Cookies:  _**We use cookies, which we place on your device to help enhance your user experience across all our platforms. Cookies are small text files that we place in your computer or device to store your preferences. Other information you provide to us may be linked to the data stored in the cookie. A cookie assigns a unique numerical identifier to your Web browser or device and may enable us to recognize you as the same user who has used our Services and relate your use of the Services to other information about you. 

We use cookies (as well as Local Shared Objects, HTML5, cache cookies, web beacons, or clear gifs, all described further below) to understand usage of the Services and to improve our content and offerings and to deliver advertisements that you might be interested in. For example, we use cookies to personalize your experience on our Services (e.g., to recognize you by name when you return to our site, to save your password in password-protected areas, to enable shopping carts, or to tailor content or product and service offerings).

Most browsers automatically accept cookies. You can set your browser option so that you will not receive cookies and you can also delete existing cookies from your browser. However, you may find that some parts of the site will not function properly if you have refused cookies or similar tracking technologies and you should be aware that disabling cookies or similar tracking technologies might prevent you from accessing some of our content. Your viewing of editorial content may be hampered. If you wish to block cookies, go to <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/> to find out how, or check your browser’s instructions.

**_Local Shared Objects:_**  Local shared objects, such as Flash cookies, also may be stored on your computer or device. Local shared objects operate like cookies but cannot be managed in the same way. Depending on how local shared objects are enabled on your computer or device, you may be able to manage them using software settings. For information on managing Flash cookies, for example, see <http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html>[ ](http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html).

**_HTML 5:  _**HTML5, the language some websites are coded in, may be used to store information on your computer or device about your Service usage activities. This information may be retrieved by us to help us manage our Services, such as by giving us information about how our Services are being used by our visitors, how they can be improved, and to customize them for our users.

**_Cache Cookies:_**  Cache cookies, such as eTags, may be used to identify your computer or device as the same computer or device that visited a Service or Services in the past.

**_Web Beacons:_**  Our websites may also use small pieces of code called "web beacons" or "clear gifs" to collect advertising metrics, such as counting page views, promotion views, or advertising responses. A web beacon is an electronic image called a single-pixel or clear GIF. Web beacons can recognize certain types of information, such as a user's cookie number, time and date of a page view, and description of the page where the web beacon is placed. These web beacons may be used to deliver cookies that conform to our cookie policy above.

**_Mobile Device IDs and Location-Based Information:  _**Certain mobile devices, including smart phones and tablet devices, contain unique device IDs that can be used to identify their physical location. Some mobile device IDs are persistent, while others may be resettable by accessing the device’s privacy settings. Mobile devices also typically transmit caller ID data (which may include a phone number) when used to transmit a telephone call or text message. When you use mobile devices to access our Services, we may collect and transmit unique device IDs and collect caller ID data, as well as other information about your device, including without limitation, your wireless carrier, the make, model, operating system, capacity and settings of your device, the names, package IDs and versions of other software you have downloaded to your device and information about how you interact with and navigate within our Service. 

**Personal Data We Obtain from Other Sources:**  
We combine personal data collected through the Services with other information that we obtain about you, your computer, and/or device from other companies and sources. To the extent we combine personal data collected through the Services with information we obtain from third party sources, we will treat the combined data in accordance with the practices described in this Privacy Policy, plus any additional restrictions imposed by the source of the data. These third-party sources vary over time, but may include:

  * Third party data suppliers from which we purchase demographic data to supplement the data we collect;
  * Social networks when you reference our Services or grant permission to Modern Dog to access your data on one or more of these services;
  * Partners with which we offer co-branded services, sell or distribute our products, or engage in joint marketing activities; and
  * Publicly-available sources such as open government databases or other data in the public domain.

The following are examples of information we may collect from other sources:

  * Name, postal address, email address and telephone number;
  * Demographic data, such as age, gender, and income level;
  * Your interests and purchase behaviour;
  * Publicly-visible data, such as your posts and submissions to blogs, video-sharing services, and other interactive forums; and
  * Other navigation data, such as web sites visited and advertisements viewed or clicked on.

**How We Use the Personal Data We Collect:**  
Our primary goal in collecting information is to provide you with a customized experience when using our Services and to make them more valuable to you. We and our authorized service providers use personal data that we or they collect about you for our legitimate interests, including to: **How We Use the Personal Data We Collect:**

  * Analyze, operate and improve our Services, and fulfill your requests for products, services, and information, including to send you emails and e-newsletters;
  * Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts, information regarding changes to our policies, and support and administrative messages;
  * Prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities, comply with applicable law and enforce our terms;
  * Enable you to participate in features such as surveys, polls, sweepstakes, and message boards;
  * Save and remember any preferences that you set while visiting one of our Services;
  * Customize the content you see when you use our Services and other services as you navigate online;
  * Attribute content that you post to forums we operate on our Services;
  * Conduct market or audience analysis and related reporting;
  * Measure and analyze visitor traffic and usage patterns and improve the quality and effectiveness of our content, features, advertisements, and other communications;
  * Analyze how subscribers interact with our email messages and click on links contained within those messages;
  * Provide you with special offers, promotions and information from companies within our corporate family; and
  * Display, develop, and deliver direct marketing.

Because our Services are supported by advertising, we also use the information we collect to help us and our advertisers efficiently reach consumers who are most likely to be interested in particular products and services. In addition, we use this information based on the consent you provide, such as if you visit our website you consent to us processing your personal data to serve you with personalized ads. Your personal data is used with your consent, including to:

  * Recognize the same users as they access online or mobile services using multiple browsers or devices and deliver to them appropriate interest-based content and advertising;
  * Provide you with special offers, promotions and information from select third parties in accordance with applicable law;
  * Tailor advertising to your interests, including advertising that you see on our Services, advertising you see on third-party websites, and email programs, and offers and advertising you may receive offline from us or others; and
  * Fulfill any other purposes disclosed to you at the time we collect your information and pursuant to your consent.

You always have the choice (now and in the future) to avoid personalized advertising based on your web browsing activity by visiting the DAA's Consumer Choice page, the NAI's website, and/or the EU online choices page, from each of your browsers or devices. For more information, see "Your-Opt Out Choices" below.

**_California Privacy Rights: Notice to California Customers:_** California's "Shine the Light" law, Civil Code section 1798.83, requires certain businesses to respond to requests from California customers asking about the businesses' practices related to disclosing personal information to third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes. Alternately, such businesses may have in place a policy not to disclose personal information of customers to third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes if the customer has exercised an option to opt-out of such information-sharing. As discussed above, if you wish to opt-out of our sharing of your information with third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes offline please email us at [info@moderndogmagazine.com](mailto:info@moderndogmagazine.com).

**Disclosure of Personal Data**  
We will not disclose, rent, sell or otherwise transfer your personal data without your consent, except as otherwise set out in this Privacy Policy or in any specific disclosure given to you when obtaining personal data from you.

**_Third Party Processors and Agents:_**  Your personal data will be transferred among our family of companies or other third parties solely for the purposes of processing your request, arranging delivery of your subscription, product, or Service, and providing customer service or other services to you. We also transfer (or otherwise make available) your personal data to third parties who administer our contests and prize redemptions, or who provide circulation audit and other services on our behalf. These entities may store and process personal data in Canada, and the United States, any other jurisdictions where they operate, where privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. For more information on international transfers, see the section "International Transfer" below. All of our service providers are required to maintain the confidentiality and security of your personal data and to use it only in compliance with applicable data privacy laws and are prohibited from using or disclosing your personal data for any purpose other than providing the services on our behalf or as otherwise not prohibited by applicable law; although we may permit them to use aggregate information which does not identify you or de-identified information for other purposes.

**_Third Party Products and Services:_**  If you are a subscriber to our publications or e-newsletters, we may share your contact information, with your affirmative consent, with carefully selected marketing partners who will contact you by mail or e-mail with offers about products and services that may be of interest to you. You can remove yourself from the future sharing of your contact information with third parties by contacting as set out in the "How to Contact Us" section below.

**_Auditing Organizations:_**  We share your personal data with third-party auditing organizations, including BPA Worldwide (CCAB – Canadian Circulation Audit Board), so they can verify aggregated statistics and circulation usage of our products or review our policies, processes, and procedures for compliance with relevant standards. You can view BPA’s privacy policy [here](https://bit.ly/2IVCDml).

**_Legal:_**  We may be required to provide your personal data in response to a search warrant or other legally valid inquiry or order, or to an investigative body in the case of a breach of an agreement or contravention of law, or as otherwise required by law. We may also disclose personal data to assist us in collecting a debt owed by you, where necessary for the establishment, exercise, or defense of legal claims, to protect the rights, property, or safety of us or third parties, or to enforce our terms

**Third Party Websites, Social Media, and Advertisers**

Our Services provide links to third party websites or offerings where data privacy practices may be different to that of Modern Dog Inc. The inclusion of any link does not imply our endorsement of any other company, its websites, or its products and/or services. These linked websites or offerings have separate and independent privacy policies, which we recommend you read carefully. We have no control over such websites or offerings and therefore have no responsibility or liability for the manner in which the organizations that operate such linked websites or offerings may collect, use, disclose, or otherwise treat your personal data.

You can access various social network posting and sharing tools through our Services that are operated by third parties, including a "share" button that allows you to post links to content and features that you believe will be of interest to others on your social network pages. When you visit a page that includes one of these sharing tools, the third-party company that operates the tool may be collecting information about your browser, device and online activity through its own tracking technologies and subject to its own separate privacy policy, which may differ from ours.

Our Services use third parties to present or serve the advertisements that you may see on our web pages, and to conduct research about the advertisements. This Privacy Policy does not cover any use of personal data that such third parties may have collected from you or the methods used by the third-parties to collect that information (e.g., cookies, web beacons, and clear gifs). For more information on tracking technologies and your rights and choices, see "Cookies and Web Beacons" above and "Your Opt-Out Choices" below.

**Your Opt-Out Choices  \- Postal Mail and Email **  
You can remove yourself from receiving our promotional e-mails by emailing us at [info@moderndogmagazine.com](mailto:info@moderndogmagazine.com) or by clicking the "unsubscribe" button that appears on our editorial or promotional e-mails. If you wish to disable web beacons in our email messages, turn images "off" in your email client (e.g., Outlook or Outlook Express) as available. Please refer to the settings or options menu in your email client for more information. You can remove yourself from our postal mailings by emailing us at [info@moderndogmagazine.com](mailto:info@moderndogmagazine.com). You can also remove yourself by contacting us as described in the "How to Contact Us" section below.

If you no longer want to receive third-party email offers, simply follow the advertiser's unsubscribe link or opt-out instructions that should be included in every message you receive from them.

**Analytics**  
Google, MailChimp, and Salesforce DMP are some of the third parties we engage to track and analyze usage and browsing patterns of our users. For information about Google Analytics’ information practices and related opt-out choices, click [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). For information about MailChimp’s collection practices and related opt-out choices, click [here](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/). For information about Salesforce DMP’s information collection practices and related opt-out choices, click [here](https://www.salesforce.com/products/marketing-cloud/sfmc/salesforce-dmp-consumer-choice/?mc=DMP).

**Interest-Based Advertising**  
Modern Dog Inc. uses Google DoubleClick for Publishers and numerous other technology platforms to help deliver relevant advertising to you. Both Modern Dog Inc. and the technology service provider may collect, receive, or use your personal data in connection with Modern Dog Inc.’s use of the platform. For information about how Google uses data from DoubleClick for Publishers, click [here](https://support.google.com/dfp_premium/answer/7670381). 

Modern Dog Inc. follows the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral advertising released by the Digital Advertising Alliance ("DAA") in July 2009. 

Most of the third-party advertising and data companies we work with, including DoubleClick and Google also subscribe to the DAA Principles and/or are members of the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI"). You can opt out of interest-based advertising from Google by visiting the [About Google Ads](https://support.google.com/adsense/troubleshooter/1631343?hl=en) page or opt out of the DoubleClick cookie by installing the [DoubleClick opt out extension](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996).

**Accessing, Correcting, and Deleting Your Personal Data**  
Modern Dog Inc. provides you with the ability to access and edit certain information that you have provided to us through our Services. To update this information, please visit the "WELCOME! [LOGIN](https://moderndogmagazine.com/user) OR [REGISTER](https://moderndogmagazine.com/user/register)" area on the top left of the webpage to enter your information. If you cannot locate such a feature, send us an email at [info@moderndogmagazine.com](mailto:info@moderndogmagazine.com). 

**Data Subject Requests**  
You have the right to access, rectify, or erase any personal data we have collected about you through the Services. You also have the right to data portability and the right to restrict or object to our processing of personal data we have collected about you through the Services. In addition, you have the right to ask us not to process your personal data (or provide it to third parties to process) for marketing purposes or purposes materially different than for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by you. You may withdraw your consent at any time for any data processing we do based on consent you have provided to us.

We encourage you to review, update, and correct the personal data that we maintain about you, and you may exercise any of your rights by emailing us at [info@moderndogmagazine.com](mailto:info@moderndogmagazine.com). Please specify in your message to us which right you intend to exercise. We will respond to your request within three business days. We may ask you to verify your identity and to provide other details before we are able to provide you with any information, correct any inaccuracies, delete any information, or exercise your rights. Your rights may be limited, subject to the law of your jurisdiction or our legitimate interests to process the personal data. Your rights are subject to our records retention policies and applicable law, including any statutory retention requirements.

**Data Controller**  
EU data protection law makes a distinction between organizations that process personal data for their own purposes (known as "controllers") and organizations that process personal data on behalf of other organizations (known as "processors"). Modern Dog Inc., located at 343 Railway St. Unit # 202, Vancouver, BC V6A 1A4 Canada is the controller with respect to information you provide through the Service.

**International Transfer**  
The personal data you provide to us is being transmitted to us and processed in Canada and any other jurisdictions where we or they operate. Your personal data will be protected subject to this privacy policy and contracts that impose data protections as required by the country where your data was collected. By using our Services, you consent to the transfer, processing, storage and access of your personal data of your personal data in and/or outside of the jurisdiction in which you reside. Courts and other authorities in these jurisdictions may, in certain circumstances, be entitled to access your personal data. If your personal data is collected in Europe, we will transfer your personal data subject to suitable safeguards, including standard contractual clauses where appropriate.

**Security of Personal Data**  
We maintain administrative, technical, and physical safeguards in an effort to protect against unauthorized access, use, loss, modification, disclosure, and any form of unlawful processing of personal data in our custody and control, and our service providers are bound to maintain similar safeguards. These measures also aim at preventing unnecessary collection and further processing of personal data. Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard the personal data in our custody and control, and we require similar safeguarding measures from our service providers, we need you to understand that we are unable to guarantee the security of your personal data.

To provide you with an increased level of security online, access to your personal data on certain of our websites may be protected with a password you select. We strongly recommend that you do not disclose your password to anyone. We will never ask you for your password in any unsolicited communication.

**Retention of Personal Data**  
We will take reasonable steps to accurately record the personal data that you provide to us and any subsequent updates. We will retain your personal data as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected. Thereafter, we will either delete your personal data or de-identify it so that it cannot be attributed to your identity. Please note that we may continue to retain personal data for purposes of our legitimate interests, including as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, prevent fraud, and enforce our agreements. Data subjects located in Europe have the right to request that we delete their personal data as set forth in the "Accessing, Correcting, and Deleting your Personal Data" section above

**Special Note for Parents**  
In general, our Services are not intended for children under 16 and we do not knowingly collect information from children under 16. If you are a parent or guardian and believe we have collected information from your child, please email us at [info@moderndogmagazine.com](mailto:info@moderndogmagazine.com). 

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
This Privacy Policy may be updated periodically to reflect changes to our personal data practices. The revised Privacy Policy will be posted on this website with the date of the last modification. We will treat your personal data in accordance with the privacy policy in place at the time of collection of such information, or as you otherwise indicate your preferences. We encourage you to check whenever you use our Services to see if the policy has been updated.

**How to Contact Us**  
If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, our data practices, or our compliance with applicable law please contact us via email at [info@moderndogmagazine.com](mailto:info@moderndogmagazine.com) or by writing to us at:

Modern Dog Inc.  
343 Railway St #202,   
Vancouver, BC V6A 1A4  
Canada
